Guide to the Mount Vernon Seminary and College Office of Student Activities records, 1988-1998 MVC0027.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mount Vernon Seminary and College Office of Student Activities records
1988-1998
1996-1998
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MVC0027.RG
4 Linear Feet 8 document boxes.
This collection contains records of the Office of Student Activities at Mount Vernon Seminary and College. The Mount Vernon Seminary began in 1875 as a private high school and junior college for women, founded by Elizabeth J. Somers. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999. The materials date from 1988–1998, with the bulk of the collection ranging from 1996-1998.This collection contains photographs, Betacam SP tapes, receipts, correspondence, brochures, and documents on numerous events, programs, and student clubs at Mount Vernon Seminary and College including Commencement, Family Weekend, and Winter Formal. The materials date from 1988-1998, with the bulk of the collection ranging from 1996-1998. The records are related to the Office of Student Activities and its role in the organization and participation of students in various activities and ceremonies held by Mount Vernon College.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains photographs, Betacam SP tapes, receipts, correspondence, brochures, and documents on numerous events, programs, and student clubs at Mount Vernon Seminary and College including Commencement, Family Weekend, and Winter Formal. The materials date from 1988-1998, with the bulk of the collection ranging from 1996-1998. The records are related to the Office of Student Activities and its role in the organization and participation of students in various activities and ceremonies held by Mount Vernon College.
Biographical / Historical
The Office of Student Activities at Mount Vernon College was responsible for student clubs and planning events and ceremonies on campus.
The Mount Vernon Seminary began in 1875 as a private high school and junior college for women, founded by Elizabeth J. Somers. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College, and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999.
Arrangement
This collection is organized by category chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection is from Mount Vernon College, which George Washington University acquired in 1999.
Office of Student Activities; Mount Vernon College
- Tennis Benefit Committee, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Tennis press, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Founder's Day, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Spring semester speaker series, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Student Government Association constitution, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Student Government Association funding, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Student Government Association constitution, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Student Governmant Association volunteer events, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Student Government Association agenda, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Scope and Contents
  Contains photographs from events on campus.
- Student Government Association agenda and events, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mount Vernon College Commencement pamphlet, 1988 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mount Vernon College comvocation pamphlet, 1992 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Student surveys, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Mount Vernon College Student and Academic Handbook, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Mount Vernon College Student Handbook, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Mount Vernon College Student Ambassador Handbook, circa 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Advertisement featuring Dr. Jane Coutant Evans, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Division of Student Affairs and Campus Life, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Articles and information on Mount Vernon College, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Memos and information on Mount Vernon College, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Student clubs and organizations, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Commuter students, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- The Voice, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Printed copies of The Buzz, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Forms for The Buzz, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Printed copies of The Toilet Tattler, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Printed copies of The Buzz and Toilet Tattler, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Event flyers, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Club news and flyers, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- National Association for Campus Activities, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Calendar information, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Calendar information, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Consortium calendar, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Master calendar, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Working and planning calendars, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Residence life, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Residence life information and flyers, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Parent's weekend, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Family weekend, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Family weekend, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Family weekend, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Parent's weekend, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Family weekend, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Family weekend, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Family weekend, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Guide for college bound students, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Mount Vernon College orientation, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Mount Vernon College orientation packet, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Orientation folder, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Parent orientation guides, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Mount Vernon College orientation, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Mount Vernon College orientation, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Mount Vernon College orientation [1 of 2], 1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Mount Vernon College orientation [2 of 2], 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Mount Vernon College orientation packet, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Mount Vernon College orientation, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Mount Vernon College orientation packet, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Environmental Awareness week, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Women's Political Action, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Earth day, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Easter egg hunt, 1993 April 3 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Cause for Aids, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Blood drive, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Nomination forms, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Campus activities, Fall 1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Student Government Association Transition Ceremony, 1996 April 10 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Aids walk, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Senior dinner, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Women's issues and programs, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Women in politics, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Celebration of the arts, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Women's History Month events, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Staff meeting notes, 1997 August 26 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Mount Vernon College Student Organization Handbook, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- La Union Latina budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- The Players budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Beacon Honor Society budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Student Design Society budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Adult Student Association budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Commuter Student Association budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Health Science club budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- College Democrats budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- College Republicans, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Girl Talk Christian Organization budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Black Student Alliance budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Campus Crusade for Christ budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- The Voice and the Phoenix, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Program Board budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Senior class budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Junior class budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Sophmore class budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Freshman class budget, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Winter formal details, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Winter formal details, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Winter formal picture proofs, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Pictures from Winter Formal, 1996 February 24 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Winter formal details, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Winter formal details, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Springfest, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Springfest, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Convocation, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Convocation and awards, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Convocation, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Convocation, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Graduation, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Faculty regalia, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Student regalia order forms, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Faculty regalia orders, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Cap and gown forms, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Student regalia orders, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Graduation information, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Seniors cap and gown forms, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Winter commencement, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Commencement, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Commencement, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Commencement, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Commencement, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Commencement, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Commencement, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Commencement, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Mount Vernon College Submaster A, 1992 June 3 (Box 8, Betacam 1)
- Mount Vernon College Submaster B, 1992 June 3 (Box 8, Betacam 2)